<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Vital Hemp, Inc. - News</title>
  <updated>2021-04-20T09:43:44-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Vital Hemp, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-april-2021-18th-b-earthday</id>
    <published>2021-04-20T09:43:44-07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:04-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-april-2021-18th-b-earthday"/>
    <title>Celebrating Our 18th B-Earthday!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Vital Ones,</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earth Day is upon us! As is Vital Hemp’s eighteenth anniversary! I founded Vital Hemp at the first Earth Day Festival in Santa Monica, 2003, so this Earth Day we are finally an adult!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As has been the tradition since 2014, I am offering a discount to my customers to celebrate!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each year, I offer an increasing percentage off everything. So this year, it’s 18% off everything at <strong><a href="http://vitalhemp.com" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a></strong> starting today (4/20) though to Sunday (4/25). Use the code:</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <strong>COOLTHEGLOBE.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are some of the ways hemp cools the globe and heals our dear (and only) living planet, Earth:</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/industrial-hemp-farming-equipmentsq_240x240.jpg?v=1618933661" alt="hemp farming" style="margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 2px; float: left;" width="240x240" height="240x240"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hemp sequesters atmospheric carbon (2 tons per acre), bringing it into the ground, the dense biomass of crops, and all the products it produces. It’s the most carbon-negative industrial crop, more effective at sequestering carbon than most forests that take years to mature (hemp takes just over three months). For every ton of hemp we harvest, it sequesters 1.62 tons of CO2!</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p>Hemp can grow almost anywhere; it regenerates the soil with nitrogen and prevents erosion. Without the need for chemical fertilizers or pesticides, hemp grows deep, dense, and resists pests. It revitalizes depleted cropland, aerating and nourishing topsoil, and serving as the ultimate rotation crop. Hemp can lead the way to more organic/regenerative farming practices that build soil health for more nutritious food, and a cooler globe.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hemp products rock! </span><strong><a href="http://vitalhemp.com" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hemp clothing</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> uses less than half the water that thirsty cotton consumes. Hemp clothing lets your skin breath, so your clothes stay fresher longer.  Fresh clothes require less washing, where most of the water consumption of garments takes place.  Hemp products also last longer, requiring less energy-intensive production. Want to cool the globe? Wear hemp!</span></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/HempinNovember2020_1024x1024.jpg?v=1618935855" alt="Vital Hemp Clothing"></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Hemp bioplastics</strong> can replace most of the petroleum-based plastics in overuse today. Currently, BMW, Mercedes &amp; Porsche are using hemp-based bioplasitics for the interior body panels of their high end cars. Why? Because it’s stronger, more durable, more heat and mold resistant, and doesn’t off-gass like the petroleum plastics; so it’s healthier for people. At the end of their useful life, hemp bioplastic products biodegrade. They don’t accumulate, pretending to be recycled while they choke our oceans and land.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Hemp building materials for happy, healthy people.</strong></span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/what-is-hempcrete-wall-1sq_240x240.jpg?v=1618933871" alt="hempcrete" style="margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 2px; float: left;" width="240x240" height="240x240"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hempcrete homes do not release harmful gases the way homes using conventional concrete do.  Plus, hempcrete is fireproof. On Earth Day 2017, I watched our old compadre, </span><strong><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/remembering-dion" title="Dion Markgraaff ">Dion Markgraaff</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, take a blowtorch to his model hemp home, with nary a mark. From Malibu to Australia, let’s build hempcrete homes, keeping our dwellings safe from the ravages of the Super Fires to come. We’ll also save on cooling and insulation costs, as hempcrete is as much as 40% more efficient than traditional materials on those fronts.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a longtime hempjucator, I feel that I’ve been sharing these facts for a decade. Actually, it’s been eighteen years. When I see hemp milk next to almond milk on the market shelf, and know it requires only a fraction of the water, and delivers three times the protein (including Omega 3’s for our healthy brains and hearts), I feel proud, and happy to have been a part of this chapter of hemp’s long history in our land and in the world.</span></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/170782079_3506733969433301_5741857917062892960_n_1024x1024.jpg?v=1618933194" alt="Ron Alcalay early days"></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hemp found me, and it’s been the project of my adult life to help it find you. My theory: it’s pretty hard to demonize the plant that made your favorite t-shirt or hoodie or pants. Turns out the “demon” has been our buddy all along, ready to be grown again. And now, as our strongest plant ally, hemp is ready to serve, cooling the globe for all our relations to live in health and peace. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With love and gratitude for you and this dear Earth we share...</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks for being vital,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ron</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span>Ron Alcalay</span><br><span>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher</span><br><span>ron@vitalhemp.com</span><br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br><span>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</span></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/remembering-dion</id>
    <published>2021-02-24T16:43:32-08:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:05-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/remembering-dion"/>
    <title>Remembering Dion</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vital Ones,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The hemp community lost a committed, visionary leader this week; and I speak for many when I say, “I feel very sad.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Dion Markgraaff</strong> was a youthful, long-time hempster, cannabis activist, visionary entrepreneur and friend to many in the industry. A short list of his accomplishments includes opening the first hemp store in Amsterdam in 1993, smuggling viable hemp seeds to the USA for planting the first domestic fields in more than fifty years, opening the first medical dispensary in San Diego, advocating for the rights of cannabis patients, and building model hempcrete houses, a passion he shared far and wide as a founding member of the US Hemp Building Association--always with a smile.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p>Although we had met before, during the nineteen years of my running Vital Hemp, we first bonded in <a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/pages/sept_newsletter2017" target="_blank" title="Kentucky blog" rel="noopener noreferrer">2017</a>, on a farm tour to the hemp fields near Lexington, Kentucky, the most impressive grow we had ever seen. Like two high rebels on the bus to school, we joked and told stories, entertaining some of our colleagues and probably irritating some others ☺. Dion embodied the truth that a person is much more than their impressive resume.    </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next time we bonded, he was standing next to a hemp house he built, in the Hemp Village at San Diego’s Earth Day festival. Blowtorch in hand, he held the flame an inch from the structure, that would not catch fire, no matter how many times he tried.  Removing his welder’s mask, he grinned, “Imagine if we start building all the homes in fire areas from hempcrete.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/Dion-church_600x600.jpg?v=1614220440" alt="Hemp Church"></span></p>
<blockquote>
<h6 style="text-align: center;">Dion's latest creation: a hempcrete church to celebrate all forms of cannabis.</h6>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dion understood that such a move would not only protect homes--a fact made abundantly clear as last year’s fires ravaged our Western states—but also help cool the globe by using an industrial crop more effective than any other in sequestering atmospheric carbon.  He definitely saw the big picture.</span></p>
<p> As those of us in the hemp industry continue to manifest our visions for a future we want to share, I believe it’s vital to pause, to recognize the unflagging, evolving commitment of our modern pioneers. People like Dion may not have personally made millions; but their work facilitates the growth of several lucrative cannabis industries. Dion battled irrational prohibition laws and regulations, always allied with those who continue to believe in the better future we see with hemp. <span>As one of those allies, I honor his work on behal</span><span class="gmail_default">f of h</span><span class="gmail_default"></span><span>ealthy ecosystems that support all life</span><span class="gmail_default">, including our own.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks for being vital,</span></p>
<p><span>Ron </span></p>
<p>Ron Alcalay<br>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher<br>ron@vitalhemp.com<br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Support your hempjucation. Learn more about <a href="https://hemptoday.net/late-activist-dion-markgraaff-inspired-and-helped-many/" target="_blank" title="Dion Markgraaff" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dion Markgraaff</a> and the <a href="https://ushba.org/" target="_blank" title="US Hemp Building Association" rel="noopener noreferrer">US Hemp Building Association</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/sharing-our-gifts-for-the-greater-good</id>
    <published>2021-01-23T16:11:33-08:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:05-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/sharing-our-gifts-for-the-greater-good"/>
    <title>Sharing our Gifts for the Greater Good</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Perhaps this is a good time for all of us to consider: what are our greatest gifts?  </span><strong>Are we using them in the service of a better life for all?  </strong><span>  </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/sharing-our-gifts-for-the-greater-good">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>It's been a long</strong></em></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>A long time coming</strong></em></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>But I know a change gonna come</strong></em></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Oh, yes it will</strong></em></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><strong><span>— </span>Sam Cooke</strong></div>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vital Ones,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I recently saw an Amazon movie called </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">One Night in Miami, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">about a fictionalized encounter between the football star Jim Brown (of the Cleveland Browns), Casius Clay (aka Mohammed Ali), Malcolm X, and the musician Sam Cooke. They discuss the past, present and future of being black in America, and what roles they can play, or are playing in the ongoing struggle. At the climax of the film, Malcolm X confronts Sam, scolding him for writing innocuous songs that appealed to white audiences, when he could do so much more with his gift. Though he earned millions crooning about love, he didn’t address the injustice in the lives of his brothers and sisters.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Powerfully, at the end of the film, having listened to the Bob Dylan song, “Blowin’ in the Wind,” Mr. Cooke composes and performs his version of “A Change is Gonna Come.” That moment in the film brought tears to my eyes, because it relates to a struggle that most of us face in life in one way or another: how do we balance taking care of ourselves with taking care of each other? How do we rise to the occasion, using our gifts for justice and the common good?  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discussing the topic of this newsletter with my marketing team, one person suggested I write something about hemp. For example: "</span><b>Five ways hemp heals the planet."</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> She had read my previous newsletters, and was surprised and moved by the enormous potential of the plant. I said, “That’s a good idea!” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though as I write, I still feel that this moment calls for something more. I want to address our national/international/existential dilemma. Is that too much to ask of a newsletter?  I understand: some of you haven’t been reading my newsletters for years. So for you, if you want to learn about the virtues of hemp and hemp clothing</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, <a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/pages/environment" target="_blank" title="Vital Hemp Environmental Page" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>visit our Environment page</strong></a></span><strong>.</strong></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/Mens_ShortsPants_Banner_jpg_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606966270" alt=""></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the rest of you, here are my thoughts about the role of </span><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="Vital Hemp website" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Vital Hemp</strong></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and my role in particular moving forward. As many of you know, after eighteen years running a brick-and-mortar store (that for the first two years was more of a booth on the Venice Boardwalk), I closed the Vital Hemp store on Santa Monica’s Main Street in March of last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The move was bittersweet, because the store had been a kind of community hub, a place where we could show documentaries, such as </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Vanishing of the Bees</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or host groups, such as the Holistic Chamber of Commerce and their guests. We threw parties with live music, produced fashion shows and offered workshops with hemp materials. Most vital, we hempjucated the public--people from all over the world--about the history, uses and benefits of the industrial hemp crop. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now the store, like so many stores and gathering places, sits empty, awaiting a time when others might re-vitalize it for a new purpose. Nevertheless, the closure freed up time and resources to focus on family, neglected projects and the e-commerce business. Among all the other losses resulting from the pandemic--in lives, jobs and health--the loss of culture, of places to gather and converse, dine, dance, learn, make or appreciate music or theater--have affected us in immeasurable ways. How can we calculate the effects on a child of not attending school in person?  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While I remain grateful for the technological adaptations, I also wonder: how has the move to a life mediated by electronics affected our minds, our bodies, and the body politic? It’s clear that social media has brought out the worst in some of us, preying upon the credulous with dangerous narratives of stolen elections and Intergalactic Covefederations, shielding us from responsibility as we bully, harangue and demonize others, seemingly without consequence…. </span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/AR_VH_selectsamples_R1-2-5678_crop_1024x1024.jpg?v=1611438944" alt=""></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p>As the son of a scientist, I’ve been on board with the majority of experts who still believe that social distancing and wearing masks--particularly in indoor spaces--is vital to controlling the spread of the virus. That’s why a friend and I started making <a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/collections/accessories/products/one-world-mask" target="_blank" title="One World Hemp Mask" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>One World Hemp Masks</strong></a>, to provide a healthier hemp alternative to the disposable masks or conventional cotton or polyester masks that dominate the market. We made a small run, sold out of some styles, and are ready to produce the next round--as much as we wish we didn’t have to do so.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The practice of social distancing so divided our intensely individualistic and social nation, that early on, I came up with the idea of “connecting with distance.” I didn’t like the ways people were avoiding each other, turning away, like we were all zombies, subject to contagion if we shared even eye contact. I began taking walks and hikes with individual friends, at a distance of six or more feet, on breezy afternoons, realizing that such a practice allowed us to connect socially--a primary need--while also being safe. This wasn’t the same as “opening up” bars, concerts and venues for political speeches.  This was just humans adapting safely to still-dangerous circumstances...taking care of ourselves and each other.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">--Which brings me back to Vital Hemp. When I founded the company in 2003, I envisioned co-creating a large company, like “The Gap of Hemp,” one that brought hemp clothing back to the masses. With a lot of experience in academia and none in business or manufacturing, I did my best. In 2010, I moved production from China to Los Angeles, finding contractors and managing production myself.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recently, a customer wrote to me, complimenting the fit of the garments he received, calling the bodies “on point.” That really made me happy, because I’ve paid a lot of attention to fit over the years.  I used to joke that it was harder for me to make a good-fitting t-shirt than to write my 296 page dissertation! I haven’t always succeeded; and sometimes, when I’ve failed, I’ve felt like quitting. Several times….</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/Resize_VH_2b679cd9-32ab-450f-b289-5235d0da4a91_1024x1024.jpg?v=1607731192" alt=""></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p>But a larger commitment motivates me, one that I share with so many in the hemp community and in the larger community of vital ones, who understand and appreciate the necessity of creating and consuming more ecologically-friendly products--not just for ourselves, but for the common good. At times, I’ve felt that I didn’t choose hemp...that it chose me.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through an uncanny sequence of events, I purchased a hemp shirt, felt the plant material on my body, felt more alive and connected with the world, and wanted to share this discovery with others. Over the years, I listened to the voice of the plant, even as I learned more about its beneficial qualities and uses from experts in the field. “Your work is not done,” it continues to tell me.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yet, with a humble appraisal of my strengths and weaknesses, I clearly understand: I cannot do this alone. Several years ago, I read a book about business that spoke of three basic roles of an entrepreneur: the Visionary (founder/planner), the Engineer (maker, or operations person) and the Seller (sales/marketing person). For most of the last eighteen years, I’ve performed all three roles. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while I still maintain and refresh the vision, I no longer have the will to overcome my deficiencies in the latter roles. I still love choosing colors, interacting with people in the vital booth at expos or festivals, and inspiring people through newsletters or talks; but these days, especially with e-commerce, the skill set requires so much more.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/VH_Ron_Banner_c30c1bda-5438-4894-b74c-600287bff8f4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1611447702" alt=""></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If I was 27 and not 57, I might know more about hashtags and marketing funnels. I might go back to school to learn about the finer points of garment construction and draping. And yes, I can still learn new things…. Nevertheless, I often challenge myself, like Brother Malcolm challenged Brother Sam: am I using my gifts in the best possible way?  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After some early promise, I developed writing skills in graduate school at UC Berkeley, where I earned a Masters in Creative Writing and Doctorate in English and American literature, teaching Composition, Literature and Film History for ten years before discovering hemp. Last year, in the midst of the pandemic, an old friend who now runs a large, public cannabis company, hired me to write press releases. I found the work satisfying for a number of reasons. First, I could vastly improve the releases they were themselves composing. Second, I knew that in promoting the company, I was contributing to their success, that in turn affects all of us.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few years ago, I visited the hemp fields of Kentucky, and experienced for the first time the palpable revelation of this tall, dense, renewable forest of sweet-smelling biomass.  Hemp fields, I learned, sequester carbon more efficiently than many forests. I don’t know exactly how the California cannabis fields in Humboldt, Mendocino or Lake counties compare to hemp in terms of sequestering atmospheric carbon; but I do know those organically-grown plants grow tall and bushy too; and they serve so many healing purposes. Writing press releases for a cannabis company growing hemp’s healing cousin feels aligned with my vision of a healthier planet, and uses my gifts in service of that goal. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">  </span></i><strong><em>    </em></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/VH_KentuckyHempField_1024x1024.jpg?v=1611633902" alt="Kentucky Hemp Fields"></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p><span>Perhaps this is a good time for all of us to consider: <strong><em>What are our greatest gifts? Are we using them in the service of a better life for all?</em></strong></span></p>
<p><span>These are times when I believe we are called upon to work together; so I’m putting this out there--for me, Vital Hemp and a future we want to share: If you have an aligned company or organization, and want some expert writing or editing, reach out to me.  My marketing team would berate me if I didn’t also mention the following: if you want to print your company logo on hemp t-shirts, hoodies or totes, please let us know.  </span></p>
<p><span>Finally, if you want to invest, or become a part or partner in Vital Hemp, send me an email with your thoughts so that we can converse. To grow, we need to work with experts in areas where I lack the expertise, expanding our small, but vital team. I still very much want this hemp clothing business to grow, from adolescence into adulthood, to flourish into its potential, because those of us in the hemp world know, “It's been a long, a long time coming… but we know, a change gonna come. Oh yes it will.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks for being vital,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span>Ron Alcalay</span><br><span>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher</span><br><span>ron@vitalhemp.com</span><br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br><span>424.268.4486</span><br><span>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</span></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/vital-hemp-new-website</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T19:28:14-08:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/vital-hemp-new-website"/>
    <title>Introducing Vital Hemp’s New Website!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks for your patience as we transition from a mostly brick and mortar</span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to an exclusively online business at <a href="http://vitalhemp.com" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a>.</span></div>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vital Ones,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This month marks the beginning of a new chapter for Vital Hemp. Today, we launch our new e-commerce website. You can still find us at </span><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">vitalhemp.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, where we are extending 20% off all styles through December 18</span>th. </p>
<p>Thank you for supporting us through the last 18 years, letting us hemp you out and cool the globe in the process. </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As you know, Vital Hemp closed its doors in mid-March, after eighteen years of selling hemp clothing to the public. Those of you familiar with our story know that I started the company on Earth Day, 2003, with a booth at the first Earth Day festival in Santa Monica. After that, I spent a couple of years peddling hemp and hempjucating the public from a temporary booth on the Venice Boardwalk, that I’d erect and tear down each day with the help of my homeless friends, who I paid $10/hr (way more than min. wage back then) and an organic breakfast from Figtree’s Cafe.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The journey spiralled outward, on road trips to Greenfests, Harmony Fests, Raw Food Fests, Natural Product Expos, Hempfests and Expos, from Seattle to Washington, DC. There, along with some other old hempsters, we informed the public and lobbied Congress people about the benefits of re-legalizing the cultivation of industrial hemp.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/AR_VH_Lifestyle_2000-Launch_24339_480x480.jpg?v=1607049662" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, it appears that the stigma around hemp is mostly gone. Hemp is so hip that we find so many products boasting about it on their packaging and in their ingredient list: hemp shampoos, hemp coffees, hemp teas….I know. I buy them all. :)  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And in eighteen years of making hemp clothing, I never bought another cotton or poly t-shirt or hoodie. I could have. I’m an adu</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">lt now; I can wear anything I want. I’ve worn hemp everyday for the last eighteen years--in every kind of weather--because it’s just better than other materials. It makes better fabric, and clothing that lets your skin breathe.   </span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/AR_VH_Lifestyle_2000-Launch_5492_sm_3a119901-fc2c-48da-a7c3-f41eb16e688c.jpg?v=1607050141" alt="womens hemp fashion" style="margin-right: 10px; float: left;" width="224" height="336">Chances are, if you’re reading this, you’re already a customer, someone who along the way bought something from us. It might have been a scarf, or a beanie, a button down shirt or some anywhere pants. I’m grateful you found us.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">  </div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Several years ago, while paying big overhead for a store on Main Street, Santa Monica, I realized that as much as I loved creating a space for hemp clothing in LA, it wasn’t the best way to realize Vital Hemp’s goal of bringing hemp clothing back to the masses. It took a worldwide pandemic for me to close the doors.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I’ve spent the Fall in a kind of early hibernation, fulfilling those few orders that have continued to come in, while preparing the virtual ground for our Winter launch. A couple of weeks ago, we produced a photo shoot with two photographers, six models, two stylists and three locations, including a friend’s modern, modular LivingHome (</span><a href="https://www.plantprefab.com/" target="_blank" title="plantprefab.com" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">plantprefab.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), and our local beach. </span></p>
<div style="text-align: right;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/WLSS_Black_480x480.jpg?v=1607050285" alt="" style="margin-left: 10px; float: right;" width="266" height="343"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was a long, fun, fulfilling day. By the end of it, one of the models said, “I can’t believe how cozy I feel in this shirt--even warmer than my cotton long-sleeve!”  I explained how hemp regulates body temperature, with this familiar feeling of having accomplished another small part of my work in the world.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To those of you who have been with us a while, and to those who are just discovering us now, thank you. While I thought of abandoning the business several times over the years, in favor or more secure or lucrative career paths, I continue to want to hemp people out.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not just because I know we’re making better, more comfortable and durable clothing than what’s out there. It’s because I know hemp is a major, under-rated part of the solution to the existential crisis of global warming catastrophes we will continue to face with ever-increasing frequency and intensity--unless we act in concert with nature to cool the globe and heal the ecosystems upon which all life depends.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We know hemp sequesters more atmospheric carbon dioxide than any other crop (and even more than many forests). As fires burn our jungles and forests, wiping out the Earth’s lungs, hemp can re-line those lungs with vital, breathing plants, plants that will transform not only our wardrobes, but our food, our medicine, our building practices and the ways we make plastics--to name just a few of the transformations to which we can look forward.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So thanks for being vital. I hope you’ll continue to support us as we cool the globe with hemp.  Thanks for letting us hemp you out.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Again, as thanks during this transition, we’re offering 20% off site-wide at </span><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">vitalhemp.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> through December 18th (no code needed). Happy holiday shopping!  </span><strong>  </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To paraphrase one of my favorite Paul Simon songs, we are “still vital after all these years.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks for being vital,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ron </span></p>
<p>Ron Alcalay<br>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher<br>ron@vitalhemp.com<br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br>Store : 424.268.4486<br>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-august-2020</id>
    <published>2020-08-11T11:37:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:06-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-august-2020"/>
    <title>Limited Supply: One World Hemp Mask!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[The One Wolrd Mask, now available in tie-dye for a limited time only.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-august-2020">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Vital Ones,</p>
<p><br><span>What times!!! And through it all, the good things persist, like a walk at the shore, a surf with sis, or tie-dye!!<br><br></span></p>
<p>When the One World Mask started, a big part of me secretly hoped it would be a short-lived project, one that fulfilled a need that went away as the pandemic went away. Alas, that has not been the case in this land, so we continue to develop and make masks. Our latest is the blue tie-dye, pictured above. We made a limited run of fifty of these, so if you love tie-dye, and hemp tie-dye even more, find them here:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.oneworldmask.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.oneworldmask.com</a></p>
<p>In other developments, we’re in the final design stage of an adjustable ear-loop style, that we look forward to bringing you next month, so stay tuned.</p>
<p><br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/OK8A7078_large.JPG?v=1598725937" alt="" width="166" height="198">   <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/OK8A6962_large.JPG?v=1598725968" alt="" width="168" height="201">   <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/OK8A7186_large.JPG?v=1598725956" alt="" width="170" height="203">   </p>
<p>In other news, Vital Hemp is happily situated in the new space, fulfilling e-commerce orders as they come in. We’re weeks away from a new site, with new photos for every style and color we produce, so please look for the announcement of the launch. “Launch” sounds so early two-thousands…do companies still launch?</p>
<p>When I was a kid, I discovered a band called The 1910 Fruitgum Company during a one-cent sale at the Warehouse record store in Westwood, California. I bought the Beatles,<span> </span><em>Magical Mystery Tour</em>, my first album, and choose<span> </span><em>Goody Goody Gumdrops</em><span> </span>for a cent. After I got into the band, I bought another album with a song called,<span> </span><em>Good ‘Ol 2001</em>. In it, the young singer praises the new world of the future, our precocious sense of progress:</p>
<p>“<em>Life is so cool: graduate high school, and then you go off to college…. About the time you’re eleven, you’re ready to sock it to the world</em>.”</p>
<p>I remember a few years ago, when parents were plugging their babies into Mozart, building little geniuses who could outsmart their peers, gaining the advantage to get into a better school, for a better career and a better life. Now, I just want to preserve my daughter’s innocence, or more accurately, her sense of a world that’s safe to experience.</p>
<p>I won’t go so far as I did a couple of years ago, when she was distraught over having lost her wiggly tooth in Whole Foods (“<em>I have nothing for the Tooth Fairy!</em>”). Nevertheless, the next morning she found a letter from the Tooth Fairy, explaining how the Market Fairy found the tooth in the cheese section, and gave it to her; so in exchange, she was giving my daughter a crystal…”<em>it’s like a tooth from the Earth</em>,” wrote the fairy. Alas, our belief in such make-believe characters fade, even as we all still want to play the game.</p>
<p>But the joy of crystals, or caves, or knitting remain. A good friend imported rugs and carpets from Tibet. He called his company Ancient Future. I think of so much of the world the same way. What is ancient and persists, will persist into our future. If it’s really good, it’s too good to go away, and will return, like tie-dye, like hemp.</p>
<p><span>Thanks for being vital,</span></p>
<p>Ron </p>
<p>Ron Alcalay<br>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher<br>ron@vitalhemp.com<br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br>Store : 424.268.4486<br>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</p>
<p><span> </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-july-2020</id>
    <published>2020-07-08T11:41:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-july-2020"/>
    <title>How to Revitalize with Deep Breaths + Hemp!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[What times! <span>Well, at least we have hemp! And clothing that doesn’t require pesticides or tons of water to make. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-july-2020">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Vital Ones,</span><br><br><span>What times!!! </span></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/VH_woods_large.jpg?v=1598726729" alt="" width="170" height="227" style="float: right;">I need to take a deep breath in and out just to continue…. I took many of these deep breaths a couple of weeks ago, when I headed North in the Vital Van with my nine-year-old daughter, on a summer camping trip up the California coast to Big Sur.</p>
<p><span>The excursion into nature revitalized us, as I knew it would. The walking in wilderness with only the sounds of sea, air and birds; the camping in a tent (and one night without it) under the expanse of stars, making up our own constellations; the chance to dunk my head under a waterfall; watch my daughter float downstream in a donut; or swim upstream in a river pool, one for a divine moment with the inexorable current.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And still, the complex world returns. Civilization and its warm comforts fill us with joy and a sense of compromise—like too many roasted marshmallows in my daughter’s tummy, or the constriction in my lungs after the campfire and the campfires of so many around us, all wanting this better, simpler life (at least for now), and all contributing to the fouling of the night air by that little stretch of river. Will someone please invent a campfire that doesn’t contribute to global warming?</span><br><br><span>Well, at least we have hemp! And clothing that doesn’t require pesticides or tons of water to make. After closing the store and moving (with great effort) to the new place, I felt a great weight lifted, and realized that the store, like a vessel that I had decorated and loved, also included a heavy anchor, in the form of overhead. In letting go of that anchor, I felt free to sail, free to create and explore uncharted territory. I feel I now have a chance to re-create Vital Hemp.</span><br><br><span>And I want to do it, because the company still has a long way before it fulfills my vision for it: the vision of a healthier, hempier world. This journey is taking us deeper into the world of e-commerce, migrating our old site from a complex platform that requires regular developer work to a simpler one that I hope we can manage ourselves, keeping it updated so we can better serve you. We also hope to continue producing and refining your favorite styles, even as we add new ones to the mix.<br><br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/logo-wear-vital-hemp-custom-printed-clothing-hoodie_large.jpg?v=1598726649" alt="Logwear" width="168" height="168" style="float: left;">On the private label and custom logowear front, we are more prepared to collaborate with other aligned brands and organizations that want to bring more hemp into the world, thereby opting for the healthiest solutions, and cooling the globe. For eighteen years, we’ve hempjucated; now the world is turning toward us, ready for the gifts.<br><br>If you’re reading this, you’ve probably already discovered what I discovered so many years ago, and decided to share with the world: the incredible feeling of hemp clothing, a feeling of communion with the world around me, a kind of magic cloak that lets my skin breath while insulating me from heat or cold. As someone who has experienced this, and wants more of it for yourself and others, I appeal to you now.</span><span><br><br>We are collecting orders for our next round of masks, and have a line sheet as well as bulk order pricing to share with you. Just ask us for it, here or through the website: <a href="https://www.oneworldmask.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">oneworldmask.com,</a><br><br>As ever, thanks for being vital.<br><br>May the sweet tides of life sooth your spirit, even in these turbulent times.</span></p>
<p>Ron </p>
<p>Ron Alcalay<br>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher<br>ron@vitalhemp.com<br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br>Store : 424.268.4486<br>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-one-world-mask</id>
    <published>2020-06-08T11:48:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T11:39:08-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/blogs/news/hempin-one-world-mask"/>
    <title>Is Your Mask Breathable + Anti-Microbial?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alcalay</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span><span color="#000000" face="verdana, geneva, sans-serif" style="color: #000000; font-family: verdana, geneva, sans-serif;">Vital Ones,<br><br>When I last wrote, I let you know that I was closing up the Vital Hemp store. It was a long week of packing up. While I had rented a storage garage, I knew it wouldn’t be big enough, and was scrambling to find other space. My intention was to find a space where I could set up a less costly e-commerce and bulk order operation. As luck would have it, the tailor, who rented space in the back of my shop for the last nine years, found a space that was too big for her. She asked if I wanted to split it. We signed the lease three days before we needed to vacate.<br><br>So I landed...like a hemp cat, leaping from a height into the unknown--unscathed, but very tired. It took two full days to recover from the move. By the way, I so love the name hempcat, I searched for the domain and found the .com was available for only $5,495! Thanks squatter. I hope you make some delicious hemp cat food or hemp vests for cats one day….<br><br>In the meantime, we are making hemp masks for humans! And the masks are ready and for sale. I teamed up with a designer, Ellie, to create a new venture, <strong>One World Mask</strong></span></span><span>®</span><span><span color="#000000" face="verdana, geneva, sans-serif" style="color: #000000; font-family: verdana, geneva, sans-serif;">. The masks are available at <strong><a href="https://www.oneworldmask.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.oneworldmask.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1598812986571000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE1VRUTJtmjT8EGs5QavwgvlHgpjw" rel="noopener noreferrer">oneworldmask.com</a></strong>, a url that cost significantly less than hempcat. These masks are the product of a months-long collaboration, testing different styles and fits, working with a pattern maker, our sewers and the dye house until we were happy. If you’ve been suffering a little in uncomfortable, disposable, or even bacteria-growing cotton masks, check out the One World Mask. Hemp lets you breath and is anti-microbial, so you can protect others in a healthy, comfortable way.<br><br>We’ve produced two basic styles in a couple of different fabrications: one with ties behind the head; the other with soft ear-loops. Three colors: natural, treetops and ocean blue. They are pre-shrunk, machine washable/dryable, soft and durable. We hope you love them as much as you love our clothing.</span></span></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/fd3ba7c8-4001-46d4-b89c-f9e0663b39e9_large.jpg?v=1598727054" alt="" width="538" height="177"></p>
<div><span><span color="#000000" face="verdana, geneva, sans-serif" style="color: #000000; font-family: verdana, geneva, sans-serif;">We look forward to making more masks for wholesale and bulk-order customers, and even have a printable style in the works that can print your company logo or original design on it. So please contact us through the site to find out more about wholesale and bulk order pricing and lead times.<br><br>As ever, thanks for your support. I look forward to sharing some new hemp clothing styles with you soon. Women’s long sleeves, tank tops and short tank dresses are in, just not on the site yet. We have more men’s hemp tees too! As soon as we unpack, we’ll revitalize and update <a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.vitalhemp.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1598812986571000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE7T7YP5mLrqH5zGhLQ_yy4vrxdnQ" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a>. ‘Til then, enjoy the One World Mask!<br><br>With love, Ron</span></span></div>
<p><span><span color="#000000" face="verdana, geneva, sans-serif" style="color: #000000; font-family: verdana, geneva, sans-serif;">Thanks for being vital,</span></span></p>
<p>Ron Alcalay<br>Founder/CEO/Hemperdasher<br>ron@vitalhemp.com<br><a href="https://www.vitalhemp.com/" target="_blank" title="vitalhemp.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">vitalhemp.com</a><br>Store : 424.268.4486<br>~Let Us Hemp You Out!~</p>
<p><span><span color="#000000" face="verdana, geneva, sans-serif" style="color: #000000; font-family: verdana, geneva, sans-serif;"> </span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="one world mask" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1662/0479/files/oneworldmask_webVH_large.jpg?v=1598727121" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
